

Madrid, Spain

🛮 (+34) 663654345 | 🗷 pablokollm@gmail.com | 🎢 www.pablokoll.com | 🖸 pablokoll | 😾 pablokoll | 🔾 en/es | 🛅 pablo-koll

## Tech skills

I enjoy discussing problems and finding possible solutions, especially when working with equally passionate people. I always seek to learn and share my knowledge whenever possible. I like working in **Linux** environments and have familiarity with cloud infrastructure, mainly with **AWS**. Throughout my career, I have developed in different programming languages, including JavaScript/**TypeScript**, Python, C++, and PHP. I have worked with various **frameworks** such as Express, Django, and React. Lately, I have focused my efforts on **NestJS** and **NextJS**. Additionally, I use **Docker** for container creation and management and **Git** for version control. At the same time, this shift has sparked my interest in various **software architecture** paradigms, such as DDD, MVC, TDD, and Clean Code.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Tendam** Madrid, Spain

IT TECHNICAL SPECIALIST & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Dec. 2024 - Present

- I work with Salesforce Commerce B2C with cartridges and pipelines, and I have experience with Salesforce Commerce Cloud (SFCC) and Demandware.
- Working with methodologies such as Agile and Scrum to deliver projects on time.
- Utilizing Jira and Confluence for project management and documentation.

#### Webmefy - Shopify Plus agency

Madrid, Spain

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Jul. 2024 - Present

- Full Stack development, implementing changes in Shopify frontends using various themes based on Liquid, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- · Integrating different systems to add new functionalities to eCommerce platforms, utilizing Shopify's GraphQL, REST, and StoreFront APIs.
- Implementing client services such as ERPs, CRMs, or various web services to enhance functionality.
- Utilizing Amazon Web Services for hosting and deploying backend applications.
- · Working closely with clients, maintaining and delivering new projects.
- · Applying Agile and Waterfall methodologies, tracking tickets and timelines for efficient project management.

#### **Balloon Group as FastForward**

Buenos Aires, Argentina

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & BACKEND DEVELOPER

Jul. 2022 - Jun. 2024

- · Self-managing projects from a technical perspective, understanding client needs, and ensuring development quality.
- Participating in the backend team for developing and maintaining software to synchronize Abbott's multi-instance Magento eCommerce with its Salesforce CRM, using technologies like Node.js, TypeScript, Express.js, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, Mocha, and Docker.
- Integrating the eCommerce system with the ERPs and carriers of Abbott's eight main countries in Latin America (Colombia, Peru, Argentina, Brazil, Ecuador, Chile, Costa Rica, and Mexico).
- Creating and maintaining middleware in NestJS, TypeScript, Prisma, PostgreSQL, Redis, Jest, and Docker, implementing functionalities for the eCommerce platforms of various clients like Circle K, VickyForm, and Indumex.
- Utilizing design patterns such as Singleton, Factory Method, Builder, Adapter, Decorator, and Facade.
- Applying authentication methods like OAuth2, JWT, API Keys, and Token-Based Authentication.
- Implementing Git for team collaboration and version control, differentiating between production, development, and testing environments.
- Developing and interacting with REST, SOAP, and GraphQL APIs for system communication.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Collaborating on infrastructure architecture using Amazon Web Services (AWS) to ensure application scalability.}$
- Implementing CI/CD pipelines on the GitLab platform.
- Using S/FTP, HTTP/S, SSH, and Webhooks for communications.
- · Applying Agile, Waterfall, and Scrum methodologies.
- Utilizing project management tools like Jira, Confluence, and Trello.

#### **Balloon Group as FastForward**

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Nov. 2021 - Jul. 2022

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- · Collaborated with the design team to create interactive and responsive user interfaces using Adobe XD and Figma.
- Worked on the maintenance and development team for Toyota's CMS, using Laravel and PHP.
- Developed multiple components in React for websites, enhancing functionality and user experience.
- Implemented communication between the backend and frontend of the application.
- Maintained a WordPress site, implementing custom functionalities using PHP.
  Applied development principles such as SOLID, DRY, and KISS.
- Developed the landing page for Toyota's Hino trucks in Argentina using VueJS to promote them.
- Prioritized the implementation of effective SEO strategies to increase website visibility and traffic.

**Henry** Remote, Latam

FULL STACK TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Bootcamp Teaching Assistant (TA) for Full-Stack Development Students.
- Coordinated a group of students to ensure their integration into the study group.
- Guided students throughout the course.
- Assisted in solving exercises and promoted group collaboration (Pair Programming).
- Reviewed the GitHub repositories.
- Proposed ideas to improve Bootcamp processes.

# **Education**

## National Technological University (UTN FRGP)

Buenos Aires, Argentina

ASSOCIATE DEGREE IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Mar. 2022 - Present

Aug. 2021 - Oct. 2021

• Currently pursuing an Associate Degree in Information Systems.

Online, Latam Jul. 2021 - Oct. 2021

**Henry**FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

• Obtained Full Stack Web Developer certification.